<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-09T14:10:45+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Toby Lam’s Blog</title><subtitle>On mathematics and tech</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Using Zoom / Google Meet with OBS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/using-zoom-google-meet-with-obs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Zoom / Google Meet with OBS" /><published>2020-08-25T10:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-08-25T10:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/using-zoom-google-meet-with-obs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/using-zoom-google-meet-with-obs.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Zoom, the control you have over your webcam footage is limited. You can either turn your camera on or off, or add a greenscreen, and that’s about it. However through OBS (Open Broadcaster Software), you could freely customize the webcam footage shown. This freedom gives various benefits. Namely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your system does not satisify the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/360043484511&quot;&gt;system requirements for virtual background for zoom&lt;/a&gt;, you could use Skype’s virtual background function to process your webcam’s footage, then stream it to Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are using google meet (which doesn’t even have any virtual background support) or pretty much any other video calling platform, you could use the above method to set up a virtual greenscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You could switch your webcam footage to any picture you like. (Maybe show a picture that says you are taking a toliet break instead of abruptly turning your camera off?)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downloads&quot;&gt;Downloads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skype.com/en/get-skype/&quot;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/&quot;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download these two plugins: &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/obs-virtualcam.949/&quot;&gt;OBS-VirtualCam&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/obs-ndi-newtek-ndi%E2%84%A2-integration-into-obs-studio.528/&quot;&gt;obs-ndi - NewTek NDI™ integration into OBS Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just keep clicking next in their installations. You do not need to edit any parameters. Make sure you have downloaded everything before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setup&quot;&gt;Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QPg5IfqAkAI&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;. Rest assured you have already installed all the prerequisites. However, there are some things you should note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As we are trying to use Skype to process our webcam’s footage, you could start a call with yourself. To do this, click meet now and start a meeting. This constitudes as an active call even though there’s only you in it. Make sure you turn on the video.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To change the OBS’s output to say a static picture. You create a new scene and add a picture to the source section. Whenever you want to show that picture, you switch to that scene. For more details, you could look at some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DTk99mHDX_I&quot;&gt;OBS tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;integration-with-zoom--google-meet&quot;&gt;Integration with Zoom / Google Meet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we need to stream whatever OBS is outputting to Zoom / Google Meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Goto OBS, Click tools &amp;gt; VirtualCam &amp;gt; Start. Remember the Target Camera’s name&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Goto Zoom, click settings &amp;gt; video &amp;gt; camera. Select the camera generated by VirtualCam.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are using Google Meet, click settings &amp;gt; video &amp;gt; camera. Select the camera generated by VirtualCam.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything’s done now! Sadly, I haven’t figured out how to stream the audio to Zoom / Google Meet. However it’s probably not worth the trouble. You would still have to directly stream your mic’s audio to Zoom / Google Meet and mute using their interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trouble-shooting&quot;&gt;Trouble-shooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cannot-find-skype-ndi-source-in-obs&quot;&gt;Cannot find skype NDI source in OBS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are in the skype call, check whether “Stop NDI” shows up on the upper left corner. If it doesn’t exist, it means you have not turned on NDI. You could turn on NDI in the middle of a call by going to settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If NDI is already turned on in your skype call and you still couldn’t find it. Turn NDI off and on again while you are in the call by going to settings. After you turn it back on, you should be able to select Skype as NDI source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lag-in-webcam-footage&quot;&gt;Lag in webcam footage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why this happens, but restarting skype seems to do the trick. Open task manager, right click on any skype instances and click “end task”. Then open skype and start a meeting …&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Motivation</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why start a website?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/11/why-start-a-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why start a website?" /><published>2020-08-11T01:45:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-08-11T01:45:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/11/why-start-a-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/11/why-start-a-website.html">&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons why I am starting this website / blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sustainabilty&quot;&gt;Sustainabilty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s becoming increasingly unsustianable to manage my profile across all social media platforms, and I believe this will only get worse in the future. The popularity of social media also changes rapidly and should one lose out on popularity, I would inevitably have to switch to another one, essentially losing all of the past posts in the process. It’s also annoying for people to have to go through multiple social media pages just to be able to have a clearer understanding or my profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flexibility&quot;&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, it’s flexible. The content that I could put here is basically unlimited (except the 1Gb limit due to github pages’ restrictions). I could type \(\LaTeX\) &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:mathjax&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:mathjax&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, make a long, organised and categorized series of tutorials and guides… This is just impossible to deliver using any other existing social media sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;portability&quot;&gt;Portability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should my web hosting fails or my domain changes, I still have a backup of the code / text that I have written. I could pratically put it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;decoupling-the-internet&quot;&gt;Decoupling the internet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the “internet” to a majority of the population is just an assortment of a few sites. Google, wikipedia, facebook, instagram, amazon etc, and I don’t think that this is what the internet should be. Everybody should have an individual precense on it. Most of these “big” sites also recommend content with a pratically unknowable algorithm. By retreating to basic technolgoies such as RSS Feeds, you will be notified whenever there’s an update to a website you’re following, hence bypassing algorithms to a minor but certain degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-touch&quot;&gt;Final touch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is open-source as it’s currently hosted by github pages. It’s free and has &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/github/working-with-github-pages/creating-a-github-pages-site-with-jekyll&quot;&gt;quite a lot of documentation&lt;/a&gt;. If you just wanna make a simple, functional webpage like this, you could take a look at the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should also mention that while Wix / Squarespace / Wordpress are options for starting a webpage, I believe I’ll just be stuck in the same cycle but one level higher. To my knowledge, it’s basically impossible to transfer the website you made with these proprietary software to anywhere else. While github pages still have their limitations, I believe it’s still not a bad starter to hosting your first website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-domains&quot;&gt;Custom Domains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve finally decided to buy a domain for this website, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tobylam.xyz&quot;&gt;tobylam.xyz&lt;/a&gt;. I used Epik and it only costed me .99 USD per year and 8.5 USD per year for subsequent years. Fortunately, github pages could still &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site&quot;&gt;host the website for free&lt;/a&gt; (essentially changing the domain name from XXX.github.io to a domain of your choice), so the costs incurred by purchasing a domain is really quite minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering how much better &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tobylam.xyz&quot;&gt;tobylam.xyz&lt;/a&gt; sounds compared to greenone092.github.io, it’s definetely worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 2021-05-08&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:mathjax&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Currently I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iangoodfellow.com/blog/jekyll/markdown/tex/2016/11/07/latex-in-markdown.html&quot;&gt;MathJax&lt;/a&gt;, it supports &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.mathjax.org/en/v1.1-latest/tex.html#supported-latex-commands&quot;&gt;a lot of symbols&lt;/a&gt; by default already &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:mathjax&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There are a few reasons why I am starting this website / blog.</summary></entry></feed>